Full Stack Developer | Data Engineer

Carlos Esteban García Márquez

Summary -

I am a Full Stack developer and Data Engineer, with three years of experience, looking to apply my computer languages knowledge, such as Python, HTML, CSS JavaScript and SQL in diverse fields, like web development and data science. All this through my communication, perseverance and creativity skills.

Life philosophy

A Dream is All I Need to Get By

Contact

- DOB: 1995-12-08, Age: 29
- charlesegm.95@gmail.com
- \square (+52) 55-19-36-82-38
- ♠ Mexico City, Mexico.
- in carlos-garcía-márquez
- CharlesItzcoatl

Languages

Spanish - Native

English - Intermediate, fluid conversation (B2)

Download my resume

Download my resume with the QR code below.



EDUCATION

2013-2018

Bachelor's Degree ESIME Zacatenco - IPN

Mexico City

Communications and Electronics Engineering Control Specialization.

Thesis: Construction and Design of an Incubator's Control System Using Fuzzy Logic Control.

tem osnig ruzzy Logic Control.

(E) EXPERIENCE

2022-Ongoing

Full Stack Developer/Data Engineer ◆ Mexico City Bubblink Digital

- Web development of consumidoresanonimos.com.
- Web development of bubblink.com.mx.
- · Web development of gfw.com.mx.
- Data manipulation and analysis for Dell with Python (Pandas). Process automation.
- Web scraping of Amazon and vvb.com.mx with Python (Scrapy).
- Web scraping of loft.com.mx with Python (Selenium).
- Web app development with Python (Flask) and Google Cloud Platform.

03/2019 -09/2019

Social Service

Mexico City

Person in charge: valverde@cinvestav.mx

- Development and implementation of fuzzy logic control systems, in hardware and software, in embedded C.
- · Temperature and humidity processing.
- Electric and electronic sensors conditioning, calculation and calibration.
- Fuzzy logic control programming in embedded C.
- I2C, UART and RS-485 communication.
- Mathematical models simulation and electronics schemes design.

X INDEPENDENT PROJECTS



Independent



- Design and development of data bases with MySQL and PostgreSQL
- ETL process doing web scraping of news websites La Jornada, SDP Noticias, Milenio and UnoTV.
- Web scraping of cia.gov to extract CIA declassified archives.
- Web scraping of website paginal2.com.ar to extract the day's news data of all the sections within the website (title, URL, date, summary, author, body and image).
- Web scraping of website etn.com.mx to extract the bus departure schedules from diverse origins and destinations (departure, arrival, duration, bus type, prices, provider, number of scales, scales characteristics).

Soft skills and strengths

Passion Dedication Perseverance Loyalty Creativity Self Confidence Planning Adaptability Teamwork Organized Interest in learning new skills Communication Work ethics | Analytical | Patience

Professional skills

Ease to learn programming languages Motivation to learn emerging technologies **Object Oriented Programming** Computational Thinking Structured Programming | Software Engineering

Other interests

- Guitar
- Books ≅
- Traveling
- Videogames
- Series N

GitHub Projects

Visit my GitHub projects:



</> COMPUTER LANGUAGES

- C/Embedded C: Intermediate
- C++: Intermediate
- · COBOL: Basic
- CSS: Intermediate
- HTML: Intermediate

- JavaScript: Intermediate
- PHP: Basic
- Python: Advanced
- SQL: Intermediate

ያ OTHER KNOWLEDGE

- Linux Command line and Terminal (Ubuntu) 3
- Bash Shell Programming 🔄
- **Robotic Process Automation**
- with UiPath 🦍
- Git and GitHub �
- RegEx (.*)

IT SKILLS

Data Analysis

NumPy 🐞

Pandas || Matplotlib

Seaborn •

Deepnote 5

Google Colaboratory ∞

Jupyter Notebooks

Web Scraping

Scrapy

Selenium 💰

Requests T

BeautifulSoup4 ---

APIs

Frontend

Development

React 🏶

Wordpress ®

Bootstrap B

jQuery &

Tailwind ~

Chakra UI 🛭

RDBMS

MySQL

PostgreSQL (**)

Backend

Development

Flask (

Office

Automation

MS Office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint) **■**

ETEX